

### **Summary**

Current Research Associate at ETS Montreal, Canada. Well-balanced academia and industry experience for more than 10 years. Research interests include deep learning, computer vision and medical imaging. 10+ published papers in the related conferences and journals, e.g., CVPR, ACCV, CVIU, etc. Also interested in applying the advanced technologies in challenging real products and environments.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**ETS Montreal** Montreal, Canada

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE Nov. 2020 - Present

- · Research areas includes deep learning, computer vision and medical imaging.
- · Responsible for providing deep learning based solutions for eye disease screening, with our industrial partner, Diagnos, Inc.
- Working with Prof. Ismail Ben Ayed and Prof. Jose Dolz.

#### Coohom, Inc. (Kujiale.com)

Hangzhou, China

ALGORITHM EXPERT & TECH LEAD OF COMPUTER VISION TEAM

May. 2018 - Mar. 2020

- · Lead the image retrieval project from zero, which provided offline and online services for the interior design product.
- Responsible for the perception system in the AI assisted interior design platform.

Qihoo 360, Co. Ltd. Beijing, China

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER Aug. 2017 - Apr. 2018

Responsible for recommendation algorithms applied in Huajiao (a live streaming app with millions of daily active users).

Alibaba Group, Inc. Hanazhou, China

SENIOR ALGORITHM ENGINEER

Apr. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- · Responsible for OCR (Optical Character Recognition) algorithms, recognizing Chinese business license, business card, bank card, etc.
- Responsible for object detection algorithms provided on the machine learning platform PAI on Alibaba Cloud.

#### Huawei Technologies, Co. Ltd.

Nanjing, China

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2015 - Apr. 2016

• Responsible for applied deep learning algorithms, supporting real applications in business partner like China Mobile.

### **Education**

#### **Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences**

Beijing, China

Ph.D. IN DEEP LEARNING AND COMPUTER VISION

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2015

- Supervisors: Prof. Hanging Lu and Prof. Jing Liu
- Got National Scholarship which was awarded to the top 1% students in China.

# **Zhejiang University**

Hangzhou, China

B.S. IN INFORMATION SCIENCE AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Sep. 2006 - Jul. 2010

- Rank: 25/210 GPA: 4.29/5.0
- · Outstanding Graduate Award

### **Selected Publications**

- Bingyuan Liu, Ismail Ben Ayed, Adrian Galdran, Jose Dolz: The Devil is in the Margin: Margin-based Label Smoothing for Network Calibration. CVPR, 2022.
- Bingyuan Liu, Christian Desrosiers, Ismail Ben Ayed, Jose Dolz: Mixed-supervised segmentation: Confidence maximization helps knowledge distillation. arxiv, 2021. (Minor revision in MedIA)
- Bingyuan Liu, Jose Dolz, Adrian Galdran, Riadh Kobbi, Ismail Ben Ayed: The hidden label-marginal biases of segmentation losses. arxiv, 2021. (under review)
- Bingyuan Liu, Jiantao Zhang, Xiaoting Zhang, Wei Zhang, Chuanhui Yu, Yuan Zhou: Furnishing Your Room by What You See: An End-to-End Furniture Set Retrieval Framework with Rich Annotated Benchmark Dataset. arXiv, 2019.
- Bingyuan Liu, Jing Liu, Jingiao Wang, Hanging Lu: Learning a Representative and Discriminative Part Model with Deep Convolutional Features for Scene Recognition. ACCV, 2014.